<!DOCTYPE writtenanswers [
<!ENTITY lt     "&#38;#60;">
<!ENTITY gt     "&#62;">
<!ENTITY amp    "&#38;#38;">
<!ENTITY apos   "&#39;">
<!ENTITY quot   "&#34;">
<!ENTITY pound  "&#163;">
]>

<writtenanswers>
<wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2002-10-22.184W.2" title="House of Lords Reform" majorheading="PRIVY COUNCIL">
<stamp coldate="2002-10-22" colnum="184W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200102/cmhansrd/vo021022/text/21022w12.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the President of the Council, if he will make a statement on House of Lords reform.  <qcode qnum="73626"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. Bradshaw" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/748"  type="reply">
		<p>The Government's objective remains to complete the reform process on which it embarked in 1997. Whether progress is possible and how fast is now a matter for Parliament itself to influence in the light of the forthcoming report of the Joint Committee of both Houses. The Government has said it will not seek to influence the Joint Committee's deliberations. We will decide how best to proceed in the light of the Joint Committee's views and the opinions of both Houses as expressed in free votes on the options defined by the Joint Committee.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2002-10-22.209W.7" title="Drugs" majorheading="SCOTLAND">
<stamp coldate="2002-10-22" colnum="209W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200102/cmhansrd/vo021022/text/21022w20.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Scotland, what steps she is taking to intensify the campaign against drugs in Scotland.  <qcode qnum="73596"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mrs. McGuire" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1072"  type="reply">
		<p>We are continuing to work with Home Office and Scottish Executive colleagues to stress the anti-drugs message and highlight drug control initiatives. The new Proceeds of Crime Act 2002 extends</p>
		<p>to Scotland and will put in place an enhanced and effective system for seizing assets from drug related crime and other criminal activity.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2002-11-06.449W.0" title="NHS Staff" majorheading="HEALTH">
<stamp coldate="2002-11-06" colnum="449W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200102/cmhansrd/vo021106/text/21106w44.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Health, what progress has been made in reducing the use of bank staff within the NHS.  <qcode qnum="59185"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. Hutton" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/987"  type="reply">
		<p><i> [pursuant to his reply, 12 June 2002, c. 1315W]:</i> I regret my previous answer contained a numerical error.</p>
		<p>The data on the overall the NHS workforce should read that it has ''increased by 4.3 per cent. to 1,166,600.'', and not, as my original answer suggested ''1,1666,000''.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2002-11-20.204W.0" title="Junior Doctors" majorheading="HEALTH">
<stamp coldate="2002-11-20" colnum="204W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo021120/text/21120w25.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Health how many junior doctors have enrolled in the NHS since 1997.  <qcode qnum="80388"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. Hutton" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/987"  type="reply">
		<p>Pre-registration house officers are doctors who, having graduated from medical school, must successfully complete a year of work in the national health service in order to achieve full registration with the General Medical Council. The table shows the number of pre-registration house officers in England in the hospital sector, including those in both medical and dental specialty areas between 1997 and 2001. We do not collect data on the number of junior doctors enrolling in the NHS each year; the census is a snapshot of data as of 30 September in the appropriate year.</p>
		<p><table>Stuff</table></p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2002-11-21.238W.8" title="Junior Doctors" majorheading="HEALTH">
<stamp coldate="2002-11-21" colnum="238W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo021121/text/21121w09.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Health what the average hours of junior doctors were in 1997; and what they were at the latest date for which figures are available.  <qcode qnum="80143"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. Hutton" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/987"  type="reply">
		<p>Data on junior doctors' working hours is not collected in a way that enables an average to be calculated. Available data shows the proportion of junior doctors who work above or below set thresholds.</p>
		<p>Initial indications from monitoring carried out in September 2002 showed 86 per cent. working on average less than 56 hours a week, with at least 23 per cent, of these working less than 48 hours a week.</p>
		<p>This compares favourably with the monitoring carried out in March 1997 which indicated that only 78 per cent. of junior doctors were working on average less than 56 hours a week.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2002-12-02.524W.2" title="Cyprus" majorheading="FOREIGN AND COMMONWEALTH AFFAIRS">
<stamp coldate="2002-12-02" colnum="524W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo021202/text/21202w16.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Foreign and Commonwealth Affairs if the UK Government will ensure that there is no division of Cyprus as part of a settlement.  <qcode qnum="84172"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. MacShane" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1083"  type="reply">
		<p>The Government welcome the UN's initiative to table a comprehensive proposal for a settlement to the Cyprus Problem.</p>
		<p>Our aim remains for a reunited Cyprus to accede to the EU, to be able to speak with one voice internationally and to have a single international legal personality. We believe the UN proposals achieve this.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2002-12-02.525W.7" title="Israel" majorheading="FOREIGN AND COMMONWEALTH AFFAIRS">
<stamp coldate="2002-12-02" colnum="525W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo021202/text/21202w16.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Foreign and Commonwealth Affairs what progress is being made in reviving negotiations between the Palestinian Authority and Israel.  <qcode qnum="84171"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. Mike O'Brien" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1138"  type="reply">
		<p>Revival of these negotiations may best be achieved through determined implementation, by the parties and international community, of the roadmap now being finalised by the Quartet. We expect its publication in December and will do all we can to support its immediate implementation, leading to a final and comprehensive settlement.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2002-12-02.530W.0" title="Fair Trade" majorheading="INTERNATIONAL DEVELOPMENT">
<stamp coldate="2002-12-02" colnum="530W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo021202/text/21202w17.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for International Development what assistance her Department is giving to the promotion of fair trade.  <qcode qnum="84501"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Clare Short" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1223"  type="reply">
		<p>Through the Development Awareness Fund, DFID has provided &pound;120,000 to the Fairtrade Foundation (FTF) over three years (2001&#150;03) in support of its efforts to target new consumers through its annual Fairtrade Fortnight campaigns. The Fortnight is designed to highlight the positive developmental impacts of fair trade and the range of fair trade products on offer.</p>
		<p>DFID is also funding a project that addresses a recognised bottleneck within fair trade&#151;namely the limited number of products for which international fair trade standards exist. This project (at a total cost of &pound;300,000) aims to develop five new product standards, secure the registration of 20 new producer groups and help bring an additional 20 new fair trade products to supermarket shelves over the next two years. The target is to increase the retail value of fair trade sales in the UK to over &pound;100 million by 2004, and by so doing, extend the benefits of fair trade to a greater number of producers in developing countries. By expanding the scale of fair trade activities, the project also aims to secure a sustainable future for the FTF, so that its core operational costs (including the cost of subsequent product development) are fully funded from the income it receives from licensees.</p>
		<p>DFID's support to the FT movement is part of a broader programme to encourage wider adoption of ethical trading codes and standards by major transnational corporations, and continuing efforts to reform the international trading system.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2002-12-05.947W.4" title="Herbal Medicines" majorheading="ENVIRONMENT FOOD AND RURAL AFFAIRS">
<stamp coldate="2002-12-05" colnum="947W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo021205/text/21205w07.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Environment, Food and Rural Affairs what the Government are doing to control the sale of endangered animal parts for eastern herbal medicines.  <qcode qnum="85386"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. Morley" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1122"  type="reply">
		<p>The Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species (CITES), which regulates trade in endangered species of animals and plants, is strictly implemented in the UK under both European and National legislation. Medicines derived from species listed in the Appendices to the Convention need an import permit issued by my Department before they can enter the country. Permits will not normally be issued for products containing the most endangered species, which are listed on the Convention's Appendix I. As a result any products that are derived from, or even claim to be derived from, Appendix I specimens taken from the wild will not normally be allowed on sale in the UK.</p>
		<p>CITES is actively enforced in the UK by Her Majesty's Customs and Excise and the Police who work together with my Department, other Government Departments and certain non-governmental organisations in the Government's Partnership for Action against Wildlife Crime. My Department produces general guidance on the Convention and maintains a dedicated website on CITES implementation in the UK. We have also worked with the enforcement agencies to produce specialist material including leaflets, posters and videos aimed directly at Britain's Chinese speaking community. We are also currently funding, with the International Fund for Animal Welfare (IFAW), research into the use of alternatives to replace certain endangered species contained in traditional medicines.</p>
		<p><page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo021205/text/21205w08.htm"/></p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2002-12-05.968W.2" title="Sporadic CJD" majorheading="HEALTH">
<stamp coldate="2002-12-05" colnum="968W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo021205/text/21205w13.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. John Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Health what the Government are doing to investigate sporadic CJD.  <qcode qnum="85388"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Ms Blears" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/737"  type="reply">
		<p>One of the Department of Health-funded National Creutzfeldt-Jakob Disease Surveillance Unit's tasks is to identify and to investigate all cases of CJD, including sporadic CJD, in the United Kingdom by clinical examination, clinical investigations, neuropathological examination, genetic analysis, molecular biological studies, collecting basic epidemiological data and carrying out a case-control study. In addition, the UK is a member of the European and Allied Countries Collaborative Study Group, which is investigating the disease within and across European countries.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2002-12-09.56W.2" title="AIDS" majorheading="INTERNATIONAL DEVELOPMENT">
<stamp coldate="2002-12-09" colnum="56W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo021209/text/21209w15.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for International Development what the Government are doing to help those suffering from AIDS and HIV in the developing world.  <qcode qnum="85389"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Clare Short" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1223"  type="reply">
		<p>My Department continues to make a significant contribution to combating the HIV/AIDS epidemic. In our bilateral programmes alone, expenditure on HIV/AIDS related work has increased from #38 million in 1997&#150;98 to over #200 million in 2001&#150;02. Major new investments include support for programmes in Nigeria, Malawi, Zambia, Zimbabwe, South Africa, Mozambique, Russia, and Ghana, China and India totalling over #350 million. We have also pledged US$200 million to the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, TB and Malaria, and #30 million to the International AIDS Vaccine Initiative and the Medical Research Council's Microbicides Development Programme. Considerable additional resources have also been committed to United Nations agencies and civil society organisations to help combat HIV/AIDS and to help people living with the disease across the developing world. We will continue to support health system strengthening and comprehensive HIV/AIDS prevention, care, control and mitigation programmes. We are also supporting access to medicines, including</p>
		<p>for HIV/AIDS. The approach of the recently launched High Level Working Group on Access to Medicines Report is to facilitate widespread voluntary differential pricing of essential medicines for the poorer developing countries as the operational norm.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2002-12-10.179W.0" title="Cyprus" majorheading="FOREIGN AND COMMONWEALTH AFFAIRS">
<stamp coldate="2002-12-10" colnum="179W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo021210/text/21210w01.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Foreign and Commonwealth Affairs what his policy is on the removal of Turkish troops from Cyprus as part of a settlement.  <qcode qnum="84357"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. Mike O'Brien" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1138"  type="reply">
		<p>The Government support the UN proposals for a comprehensive settlement in Cyprus, which allow for there to be between 1,000 and 9,999 troops from both Greece and Turkey on the island. It is of course for the two sides in Cyprus to agree a settlement, but we believe the UN proposals to be workable and fair.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2002-12-10.242W.1" title="Sexual Offenders Register" majorheading="HOME DEPARTMENT">
<stamp coldate="2002-12-10" colnum="242W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo021210/text/21210w18.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for the Home Department how many people are on the Sexual Offenders Register; and how many were on the register in 1997.  <qcode qnum="85384"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Hilary Benn" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/727"  type="reply">
		<p>The Sex Offenders Act 1997 requires offenders cautioned for, convicted of, or found not guilty by reason of insanity of an offence specified in Schedule One to the Act since the date of its implementation to notify the police of their names, addresses, dates of birth and intentions to travel abroad for eight days or longer. The requirements of the Act also apply to offenders who were serving a sentence for a relevant offence, either in prison or in the community, at the date of its implementation (1 September 1997). There is, however, no central register of sex offenders and offenders subject to the requirements of the Sex Offenders Act are not separately identified in criminal statistics.</p>
		<p>Information on the number of 'registered' sex offenders in a police area is submitted by police and probation services under the requirements placed on them established by section 67 of the Criminal Justice and Court Services Act 2000.</p>
		<p>As at 31 March 2002, police forces in England and Wales had notified the Home Office of 18,513 'registered' sex offenders.</p>
		<p>I am informed by the Scottish Executive that as at 28 August 2002, 1,816 registered sex offenders were recorded by the Scottish Criminal Record Office as being administered by Scottish Police Forces.</p>
		<p>The provisions of the Sex Offenders Act 1997 were commenced on 1 September 1997. A Home Office evaluation of the way the Act had been implemented was published in July 2000. This indicated that at 31 August 1998, one year after implementation, 8,608 sex offenders were subject to the Act's requirements. Figures covering the last three months of 1997 are not available.</p>
		<p><page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo021210/text/21210w19.htm"/></p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2002-12-10.297W.0" title="Herbal Remedies" majorheading="HEALTH">
<stamp coldate="2002-12-10" colnum="297W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo021210/text/21210w32.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Health what the Government are doing to regulate herbal remedies that they estimate could endanger people's health if taken in large enough quantities.  <qcode qnum="85387"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Ms Blears" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/737"  type="reply">
		<p>Potentially any herbal remedy could put health at risk if taken in sufficient quantity. The proposed Directive on Traditional Herbal Medicinal Products is under negotiation in Europe. The current proposals would ensure that traditional herbal remedies registered under the scheme were accompanied by systematic information about dosage and other information relating to the safe use of the product. This contrasts with the current position for unlicensed remedies under Section 12(2) of the Medicines Act 1968 where there are no such specific requirements for information to be given.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2002-12-17.726W.4" title="Submarines" majorheading="DEFENCE">
<stamp coldate="2002-12-17" colnum="726W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo021217/text/21217w13.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Defence what action he plans to take in response to the National Audit Office report on submarine refitting at Devonport.  <qcode qnum="87765"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. Ingram" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/990"  type="reply">
		<p>The report, while acknowledging that lessons for future projects have been identified by the Ministry of Defence, made a number of further recommendations. These are being considered in detail and, where appropriate, will be applied to MOD projects.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2002-12-19.908W.3" title="Sustainable Crops (Africa)" majorheading="INTERNATIONAL DEVELOPMENT">
<stamp coldate="2002-12-19" colnum="908W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo021219/text/21219w06.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for International Development what assistance the UK is giving the underdeveloped countries of Africa to produce sustainable crops.  <qcode qnum="87766"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Clare Short" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1223"  type="reply">
		<p>My Department works with developing countries to ensure that their poverty reduction strategies reflect the need to manage environmental resources, including agricultural production, sustainably. Sustainability must be seen in its widest context. It is not just a matter of the ecology of agricultural systems themselves, but the impact of these systems on the lives and opportunities of others, particularly poor consumers and producers. Sustainability in one system cannot be at the expense of sustainability in others.</p>
		<p>My Department also supports a significant number of programmes and projects throughout the developing world that seek to provide direct benefits to poor people whose livelihoods are dependent on agriculture. Many of these include the provision of support to sustainable agriculture, either through training and knowledge/technology transfer, institutional capacity building and reform (e.g. strengthening co-operatives and other forms of producer groups and improving agricultural service delivery) or the funding of research, both national and international.</p>
		<p>This year, DFID expects to spend about #35 million on natural resources research. While sustainability is a cornerstone for all our research programmes, a significant proportion of the programme is focused on developing and transferring technologies specifically for sustainable agriculture.</p>
		<p>Copies of the DFID issues paper XBetter Livelihoods for Poor People: The Role of Agriculture and the Renewable Natural Resources Research Strategy" publication are available in the Libraries of the House.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2002-12-19.945W.3" title="Sandy Mitchell" majorheading="FOREIGN AND COMMONWEALTH AFFAIRS">
<stamp coldate="2002-12-19" colnum="945W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo021219/text/21219w16.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Foreign and Commonwealth Affairs what talks he has had with the Saudi Arabian government on the imprisonment of a constituent, Sandy Mitchell.  <qcode qnum="87300"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. Mike O'Brien" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1138"  type="reply">
		<p>My right hon. Friend the Foreign Secretary, and ministerial colleagues have raised the cases of Mr. Mitchell and the other British men detained in Saudi Arabia at the highest levels with the Saudi authorities. We remain deeply concerned about these cases. The men's welfare is our paramount concern. We continue to work tirelessly to resolve the cases. We are in close contact with the Saudi authorities and the men's lawyers. We also continue to make consular visits to the men.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2002-12-19.1037W.5" title="Acute Trusts (Nurses)" majorheading="HEALTH">
<stamp coldate="2002-12-19" colnum="1037W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo021219/text/21219w38.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Health what the level is of nurse understaffing in England's acute trusts.  <qcode qnum="87767"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. Hutton" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/987"  type="reply">
		<p>Levels of staffing are a matter for individual trusts. The three month vacancy rate is an indicator of the number of posts in their establishment which trusts are finding difficult to fill.</p>
		<p>Information on the level of three month vacancies in acute trusts in England will be placed in the Library.</p>
		<p>Between March 2001 and 2002 the three month vacancy rate for qualified nurses fell from 3.4 per cent., to 3.1 per cent. This is the second successive fall for nurse vacancies and shows that our recruitment and retention policies are bearing fruit.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-01-07.72W.0" title="Staff Bonuses" majorheading="CABINET OFFICE">
<stamp coldate="2003-01-07" colnum="72W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo030107/text/30107w19.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Minister for the Cabinet Office</p>
		<p>(1) how much each Government Department has paid in bonuses to staff who achieved personal targets in this financial year;  <qcode qnum="88303"/></p>
		<p>(2) how many Departments which have failed to achieve Government targets have paid staff bonuses. <qcode qnum="88304"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. Alexander" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/693"  type="reply">
		<p>Responsibility for pay, outside of the senior civil service, is delegated to Departments and agencies. What bonuses are paid to these staff is therefore a matter for individual Departments and agencies. This Information is not held centrally.
		The new pay and performance management arrangements for the senior civil service are designed to reward and provide incentives for high performance. Under these arrangements all Departments awarded non-consolidated bonuses to their top performers.
		Performance bonuses totalling #6 million were paid to those who contributed most to their Department's objectives. Bonuses were paid to around 55 per cent. of senior civil service staff.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-01-07.141W.6" title="Suicides (Youth Detention)" majorheading="HOME DEPARTMENT">
<stamp coldate="2003-01-07" colnum="141W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo030107/text/30107w36.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for the Home Department</p>
		<p>(1) how many <i>(a)</i> young people and <i>(b)</i> women have committed suicide in youth detention in each year since 1997;  <qcode qnum="87764"/></p>
		<p>(2) how many suicides there have been in English prisons in each year since 1997.  <qcode qnum="87763"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Hilary Benn" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/727"  type="reply">
		<p>The information requested is in the tables. Table 1 covers the 468 self-inflicted deaths in Prison Service establishments in England since 1 January 1997. Table 2 covers the 71 male and eight</p>
		<p>female self-inflicted deaths of those under the age of 21 held in Prison Service establishments in England and Wales since 1 January 1997. Those under the age of 18 may also be held in Local Authority Secure Units and Secure Training Centres (STCs). Table 3 covers the one self-inflicted death in Local Authority Secure Units in England and Wales since 1 January 1997. There have been no deaths in STCs since the first STC opened in April 1998.</p>
		<p><table>Stuff</table></p>
		<p><table>Stuff</table></p>
		<p><table>Stuff</table></p>
		<p>The Prison Service and the Youth Justice Board (YJB) are working closely together to try to prevent the suicides of young people held in their care. The Prison Service's suicide prevention and self-harm reduction programme (which applies to all prisoners, regardless of gender and age) includes a series of projects to improve pre-reception, reception and induction arrangements; the exchange of information; the care of prisoners; detoxification; prisoners supporting each other and learning from investigations into deaths in custody.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-01-14.520W.1" title="Digital Hearing Aids" majorheading="HEALTH">
<stamp coldate="2003-01-14" colnum="520W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo030114/text/30114w04.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Health how much trusts in England and Wales allocated to digital hearing aids in the last year for which figures are available.  <qcode qnum="90226"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Jacqui Smith" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1234"  type="reply">
		<p>The Department of Health has allocated #30.75 million to its modernising hearing aid services project over the financial years 2000&#150;01 to 2002&#150;03 to national health service trusts in England. This modernised service includes the provision of digital hearing aids. Twenty sites joined the project in the first wave, with a further 30 second-wave sites joining in 2002&#150;03.</p>
		<p>For second wave sites the Department pays the cost of upgrading information technology and other systems, 75 per cent. of additional staff costs and 75 per cent. of the difference between the cost of providing digital and analogue aids. Local primary care trusts pay the remaining 25 per cent. of revenue costs.</p>
		<p>A further 17 sites will be receiving training and equipment, this financial year, to allow them to dispense digital hearing aids.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-01-14.531W.4" title="Nursing Vacancies" majorheading="HEALTH">
<stamp coldate="2003-01-14" colnum="531W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo030114/text/30114w07.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Health how many nursing vacancies exist in trusts in England and Wales.  <qcode qnum="90225"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. Hutton" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/987"  type="reply">
		<p>Information on vacancies lasting three months or more for nursing staff in England is shown in the table.</p>
		<p>The three month vacancy rate was 3.1 per cent. in March 2002, a fall from 3.4 per cent. in March 2001 and the second successive fall in vacancies for qualified nursing staff.</p>
		<p>Information for Wales is a matter for the National Assembly for Wales.</p>
		<p><table>Stuff</table></p>
		<p><i>Notes:</i></p>
		<p>1. Three month vacancy information is as at 31 March 2002.</p>
		<p>2. Three month vacancies are vacancies which trusts are actively trying to fill, which had lasted for three months or more (whole-time equivalents).</p>
		<p>3. Three month Vacancy Rates are three month vacancies expressed as a percentage of three month vacancies plus staff in post.</p>
		<p>4. Three month Vacancy Rates are calculated using staff in post from the Vacancy Survey, March 2002.</p>
		<p>5. Staff in post data is from the Non-Medical Workforce Census, September 2001.</p>
		<p>6. Staff in post data excludes staff employed by Health Authorities, as vacancy information was only collected from Trusts, PCTs and Special Health Authorities.</p>
		<p>7. Percentages are rounded to one decimal place.</p>
		<p>8. Calculating the vacancy rates using the above data may not equal the actual vacancy rates.</p>
		<p><i>Sources:</i></p>
		<p>Vacancy Numbers and Rates: Department of Health Vacancies Survey March 2002</p>
		<p>Non Medical Staff in Post: Department of Health Non-Medical Workforce census September 2001</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-01-16.793W.4" title="Illegal Working Practices" majorheading="TRADE AND INDUSTRY">
<stamp coldate="2003-01-16" colnum="793W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo030116/text/30116w26.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Trade and Industry what the Government are doing to combat illegal working practices and how many companies have been prosecuted since 1997 for such practices.  <qcode qnum="85385"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Malcolm Wicks" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1316"  type="reply">
		<p>I have been asked to reply.</p>
		<p>The Department for Work and Pensions is focusing increasingly on fraud where dishonest employers abuse the system, for example by not paying national insurance contributions or by paying artificially low wages to workers who continue to claim out-of-work benefits.</p>
		<p>We have put in place a programme targeting these employers and have specialist teams working together with the Inland Revenue and HM Customs and Excise to tackle employer fraud, including Joint Shadow Economy Teams. In addition we have since 1 May 2002 had powers under the Fraud Act to impose a financial</p>
		<p>penalty on employers who abuse the system instead of prosecuting them. This new power, together with the work we are doing jointly with the taxation Departments, marks a step change in our approach to those employers who would collude with their employees in cheating the tax or benefit systems.</p>
		<p>Information on the number of employers prosecuted specifically for collusion is not available and could be obtained only at disproportionate cost.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-01-21.223W.4" title="Iraq" majorheading="FOREIGN AND COMMONWEALTH AFFAIRS">
<stamp coldate="2003-01-21" colnum="223W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo030121/text/30121w06.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Foreign and Commonwealth Affairs if he will make a statement on the action the UK Government will take should the UN decide not to take military action against Iraq.  <qcode qnum="91804"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. Rammell" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1179"  type="reply">
		<p>In the event that there is a material breach, the preference of the British Government is for a second resolution. So far, the UN Security Council has, as Kofi Annan has said, &quot;faced up to its responsibilities". We believe it will continue to do so. But we must reserve our position in the event that it does not.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-01-21.223W.6" title="Iraq" majorheading="FOREIGN AND COMMONWEALTH AFFAIRS">
<stamp coldate="2003-01-21" colnum="223W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo030121/text/30121w06.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Foreign and Commonwealth Affairs for what reason the report from Iraq on weapons of mass destruction was not presented in its entirety to the UN.  <qcode qnum="91514"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. Rammell" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1179"  type="reply">
		<p>Under relevant non-proliferation conventions, China, France, the Russian Federation, the United Kingdom and the United States of America are obliged to prevent the dissemination of information relating to the production of biological, chemical, and nuclear weapons.</p>
		<p>The President of the UN Security Council therefore decided that the full Iraqi declaration should only be given to these members of the Security Council, who</p>
		<p>also have the expertise to assess the risks of proliferation. His decision followed consultations with all members of the Security Council.</p>
		<p>The other members received the main body of the Declaration excluding a number of sensitive passages and words that were omitted by UNMOVIC and the IAEA who, after consulting the Security Council members with expertise to assess the risks of proliferation, judged them to contain information that might be of use to potential WMD proliferators.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-01-21.225W.3" title="Cyprus (Missing People)" majorheading="FOREIGN AND COMMONWEALTH AFFAIRS">
<stamp coldate="2003-01-21" colnum="225W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo030121/text/30121w07.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Foreign and Commonwealth Affairs what discussions he has had with the new Turkish Government on what has happened to the people missing since the Turkish invasion of Cyprus.  <qcode qnum="91526"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. MacShane" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1083"  type="reply">
		<p><i>[holding answer 20 January 2003]</i>: We share the concerns of both the Greek Cypriot and Turkish Cypriot communities over the missing persons following the events of 1974. However, this is a humanitarian issue on which the UN Committee on Missing Persons, established in 1983, leads. We support the actions of the Committee and urge full co-operation with it.</p>
		<p>Such humanitarian concerns are among the many reasons why we urge both sides in Cyprus to achieve a settlement, based on the UN Secretary-General's proposals of 10 December, by the UN deadline of 28 February. My right hon. Friend the Prime Minister and I reiterated Her Majesty's Government's support for an early settlement when we met Turkish Ministers at the Copenhagen European Council in December. My right hon. Friend the Secretary of State for Defence did likewise during his visit to Ankara on 8 January.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-01-21.303W.0" title="Female Fine Defaulters" majorheading="HOME DEPARTMENT">
<stamp coldate="2003-01-21" colnum="303W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo030121/text/30121w25.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for the Home Department how many women were jailed for failing to pay fines in <i>(a)</i> 2002 and <i>(b)</i> 1997.  <qcode qnum="91092"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Hilary Benn" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/727"  type="reply">
		<p>The number of female fine defaulters received into prisons in England and Wales in 2001 (the latest complete year for which data is available) was 73, and in 1997 was 372.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-01-22.309W.0" title="Angola" majorheading="INTERNATIONAL DEVELOPMENT">
<stamp coldate="2003-01-22" colnum="309W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo030122/text/30122w02.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for International Development what assistance the Government is giving to Angola in the clearance of landmines.  <qcode qnum="91819"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Clare Short" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1223"  type="reply">
		<p>My Department has allocated &pound;300,000 to UNDP for a project aimed at improving the effectiveness of mine action through strengthened co-ordination at the provincial level. DFID has also contributed US$ 50,000 in support of a mine action database. The United Kingdom contributed 19.7 per cent. of the 6 million euros which the EC has made available for mine action in Angola. This included 5 million euros to a variety of mine clearance agencies.</p>
		<p>The United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs recently contributed US$460,000 from its Emergency Response Fund for Angola (ERF) to clear the mines from some of the main transport arteries used to deliver emergency supplies. The United Kingdom was one of the main donors to this fund in 2002, contributing &pound;1.5 million.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-01-27.630W.4" title="Iraq (Post-conflict)" majorheading="DEFENCE">
<stamp coldate="2003-01-27" colnum="630W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo030127/text/30127w30.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Defence what role British troops will have in a post-conflict Iraq.  <qcode qnum="93187"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. Ingram" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/990"  type="reply">
		<p>There is no inevitability about military action against Iraq; this question is therefore hypothetical at this stage. What I can say is that we take very seriously our current and potential responsibilities towards the Iraqi people. In the aftermath of any conflict, Britain would remain at the forefront of efforts to help the Iraqi people.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-01-28.837W.4" title="Iraq" majorheading="DEFENCE">
<stamp coldate="2003-01-28" colnum="837W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo030128/text/30128w30.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Defence whether British troops have been given orders in relation to protection of oil fields in Iraq.  <qcode qnum="93105"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. Hoon" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/970"  type="reply">
		<p>No decision has been taken to commit British forces to military action against Iraq. It would not be appropriate to comment on any tasks that might be undertaken by our forces in the event of military operations.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-01-30.990W.2" title="Civil Servants (Bonus Payments)" majorheading="TREASURY">
<stamp coldate="2003-01-30" colnum="990W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo030130/text/30130w12.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Chancellor of the Exchequer how much was paid in bonus payments to civil servants in 2001&#150;02 related to performance in his Department. <qcode qnum="92950"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Ruth Kelly" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1014"  type="reply">
		<p>During the financial year 2001&#150;02 a total of &pound;274,980 in performance bonus payments was paid to staff.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-02-04.208W.2" title="Civil Servants (Bonus)" majorheading="CULTURE MEDIA AND SPORT">
<stamp coldate="2003-02-04" colnum="208W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo030204/text/30204w21.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Culture, Media and Sport how many civil servants in her Department received bonuses having attained personal targets in the last financial year; and what the value was.  <qcode qnum="94581"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Dr. Howells" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/978"  type="reply">
		<p>The number of civil servants who received bonuses, having attained personal targets in my Department in the last financial year, was 89. They received bonuses of between &#163;750 and &#163;3,500, with an overall value of &#163;116,400.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-02-25.502W.1" title="Acute Trusts" majorheading="HEALTH">
<stamp coldate="2003-02-25" colnum="502W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo030225/text/30225w31.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Health how many people from outside the UK were treated in acute trusts in 2001&#150;02.  <qcode qnum="97985"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. Hutton" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/987"  type="reply">
		<p>The information requested is not collected centrally.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-03-25.135W.4" title="Iraq" majorheading="INTERNATIONAL DEVELOPMENT">
<stamp coldate="2003-03-25" colnum="135W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/cm030325/text/30325w07.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for International Development how many countries will be involved in the reconstruction of Iraq.  <qcode qnum="104737"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Clare Short" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1223"  type="reply">
		<p>It is too soon to say how many countries might be involved. UN mandate will be required to provide legal authority for the reconstruction effort, and to make possible the engagement of the International Financial Institutions and the wider international community. The Government is working to ensure such a mandate is put in place.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-03-27.351W.4" title="Iraq" majorheading="INTERNATIONAL DEVELOPMENT">
<stamp coldate="2003-03-27" colnum="351W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/cm030327/text/30327w14.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for International Development how much UK will invest in reconstruction and aid to Iraq in 2003&#150;04.  <qcode qnum="104728"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Clare Short" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1223"  type="reply">
		<p>My Department has an ongoing programme of humanitarian support to the people of Iraq which is delivered through NGOs and international organisations. This programme is allocated &#163;6 million in 2003&#150;04.</p>
		<p>In addition, I have committed &#163;50 million to support preparations and work by humanitarian agencies in the current crisis. This includes &#163;32 million for the Red Cross/Red Crescent and &#163;8 million for the World Food Programme. My Department has a further &#163;40 million set aside for the immediate humanitarian response and is considering further assistance in line with emerging needs.</p>
		<p>DFID also provides 19 per cent. of European Community (EC) funding for Iraq. On 21 March the College of European Commissioners proposed to release an additional Euro79 million from their Emergency Aid Reserve, increasing their total commitment to Euro100 million. This funding is still to be approved by the European Council.</p>
		<p>It is too soon to allocate funds for the post-war reconstruction of Iraq.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-04-02.733W.7" title="Aircraft Carriers" majorheading="DEFENCE">
<stamp coldate="2003-04-02" colnum="733W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/vo030402/text/30402w10.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Defence what progress is being made in joint working between Thales and BAE Systems on the aircraft carriers order.  <qcode qnum="105419"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. Ingram" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/990"  type="reply">
		<p>Our discussions with BAE Systems and Thales to determine the structure of the Alliance for the Future Aircraft Carrier programme are continuing. During the course of those discussions, BAE Systems and Thales have been working together extensively and</p>
		<p>design activity has continued in parallel. We expect to be in a position to commence formal joint working on the next phase of assessment shortly. Subject to the normal internal approvals, we remain on course to award the main build contract for the carriers in the spring of 2004.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-05-08.790W.0" title="Global Health Fund" majorheading="TREASURY">
<stamp coldate="2003-05-08" colnum="790W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/cm030508/text/30508w04.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Chancellor of the Exchequer what proposals he has to finance the Global Health Fund.  <qcode qnum="111893"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="John Healey" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/949"  type="reply">
		<p>The Department for International Development has committed $200 million to the Global Fund to fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria over five years.</p>
		<p>In addition, the Treasury is seeking international support to establish the International Finance Facility, which will raise $50 billion annually to fund the Millennium Development Goals. This money would be disbursed in the form of concessional loans and grants, including debt relief.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-06-10.796W.0" title="Afghanistan" majorheading="FOREIGN AND COMMONWEALTH AFFAIRS">
<stamp coldate="2003-06-10" colnum="796W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/cm030610/text/30610w22.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Foreign and Commonwealth Affairs if he will make a statement on progress of the campaign to restrict the supply of drugs from Afghanistan.  <qcode qnum="117394"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. Mike O'Brien" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1138"  type="reply">
		<p>The Afghan Transitional Administration adopted a national drug strategy on 19 May. The UK has committed &#163;70 million over the next three years to assist in the objective of eliminating opium poppy from Afghanistan and will post additional British Embassy personnel to Kabul in the coming months to help the Afghan Transitional Administration to achieve their objective.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-06-18.325W.0" title="Cat and Dog Fur" majorheading="TRADE AND INDUSTRY">
<stamp coldate="2003-06-18" colnum="325W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/cm030618/text/30618w32.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Trade and Industry what action she is taking to prevent the trade in cat and dog fur.  <qcode qnum="117396"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Ms Hewitt" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/960"  type="reply">
		<p>The Government are investigating possibilities for labelling any products that may contain domestic cat and dog fur. Equally we are working to ensure a reliable scientific test is in place to validate the accuracy of any such labels. This will give consumers the information they want about exactly what they are buying. We will report back to Parliament before summer recess.</p>
		<p>It has not proved possible to determine either through trade statistics or through scientific testing, what level of imports of these products, if any, is entering the UK. Therefore the Government do not consider any more trade-restrictive action to be proportionate to the scale of the problem at this time.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-07-01.202W.3" title="Cyprus" majorheading="FOREIGN AND COMMONWEALTH AFFAIRS">
<stamp coldate="2003-07-01" colnum="202W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/cm030701/text/30701w06.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Foreign and Commonwealth Affairs if he will make a statement on the situation in Cyprus.  <qcode qnum="117393"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. MacShane" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1083"  type="reply">
		<p>I refer my hon. Friend to the written ministerial statement made by my right hon. Friend the Foreign Secretary on 4 June 2003, <i>Official Report</i>, column 22WS.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-11-11.274W.2" title="Trust Performance Ratings" majorheading="HEALTH">
<stamp coldate="2003-11-11" colnum="274W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/cm031111/text/31111w29.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Health if he will list the performance ratings for <i>(a)</i> acute and <i>(b)</i> specialist trusts for 2002&#150;03.  <qcode qnum="135921"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Mr. Hutton" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/987"  type="reply">
		<p>Information on the performance ratings for 2002&#150;03 for all organisation types are available in the Library and on the Commission for Health Improvement's website at www.chi.nhs.uk/ratings.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans><wrans id="uk.org.publicwhip/wrans/2003-11-12.386W.7" title="Civil Servants" majorheading="WORK AND PENSIONS">
<stamp coldate="2003-11-12" colnum="386W"/>
<page url="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm200203/cmhansrd/cm031112/text/31112w29.htm"/>
	<speech name="Mr. Lyons" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/1060"  type="ques">
		<p>To ask the Secretary of State for Work and Pensions how many civil servants in the Department achieved personal bonus targets in 2002&#150;03; and what the total value of personal bonus targets was.  <qcode qnum="132796"/></p>
	</speech>
	<speech name="Maria Eagle" id="uk.org.publicwhip/member/872"  type="reply">
		<p>The Department does not operate a personal bonus target scheme. However, we estimate that approximately 110,000 staff achieved a level of performance during 2002&#150;03 to qualify for a performance bonus as part of the forthcoming 2003 pay settlement. The settlement has not yet been finalised, but expenditure on performance bonuses last year amounted to &#163;24.75 million.</p>
	</speech>
</wrans>
</writtenanswers>
